If you are newly married or you are planning a baby then
this video is for you.
Maternity by default is
not covered in your insurance policies.  For maternity,
you have to take add-ons or maternity
specific plans.  So today
we will talk about the top six
maternity plans that you can consider
if you want to cover maternity
in your policy.  Delivery is covered in maternity.
Newborn baby expenses are covered.
Vaccinations are covered and
much more, but some come with a waiting period.
So let us understand which policies
are there and when you can take them to cover your
maternity expenses.
[Music]
A quick reminder before we start the video,
if you haven't already, please subscribe to our channel.
So that you
get the right infection at the right time.  Let's move on to the
video.  Top Six Maternity
Pluses for 2026.  So here we will compare six plans.
What are those plans?   The
first one is Neevapa Aspire Plan Titanium
Plus, HDFCO Optima Secure, ICIC LBD
Elevate Base Plan, Aditya Birla Activ Fit
Preferred Plan, Manipal Cigna Sarvaha
Uttam and Star Women Care. We will compare these six plans.
First let us see
what is the Incred Claim Ratio of these companies, that is,
how much premium was collected and how much was
paid out in claims, it is called
Incred Claim Ratio, so Neeva's is 61.22%,
HDFC Ago is 84.85%,
ICIC LB is 82.24%, Aditya Birla is 71.5%,
Manipal Cigna is 74.81%, Star Health is
70.3%. This is the latest report of IADA on this, the
data is of Age on 31 March 2025.
So now let's talk about
when you should take a maternity plan?  Meaning, when
can you avail maternity?  When should you buy a policy that
offers maternity benefits?  So the first
five plans which are Niva
Aspire, HDFC Ergo Optima Secure, ICICI
Daily Weight, Aditya Birla Active Fit and
Manipal Singhana Sir Uttam, in this you have to take the policy
before conception, that is,
you have to take the policy before conceiving, only then you will
get maternity benefits, after getting
pregnant you will not get maternity benefits,
in Wares Star Women Care also you have to take it before
conception, pregnant
ladies can take it, maternity claim will not be
available, newborn baby expenses can be claimed,
if that too is in a few months, that is,
in this month you will be able to get the policy on the basis of your scans
and 25% of the sum
assured which is newborn baby expenses will be
covered.  Talk about maternity coverage.
Maternity cover is
different from your sum assured.  Maternity cover is a
fixed benefit which is a fixed amount that
you get in your policy
irrespective of your claim i.e.
₹70000 to ₹1 lakh depending on the sum
assured and the policy you choose.  So
you have it built into Aspire.  There is no need to take add on in this.
Your Miracle Benefit
is inbuilt.  There is a waiting period of nine months in this.
So the minimum waiting period is for you
in Aspire.
You can avail maternity benefits after a waiting period of 9 months.  This
means that you have to take the policy before conception.
And the maternity benefit which
we call miracle benefit is
available up to ₹75,000.   It will
depend on whether you are taking sum assured.   It will
depend, if you are taking a three year fast
forward policy then
you will get more cover and so on.  HDFC
Optima Secure has a parenthood rider
which you have to choose.  It comes with a two-
year waiting period.
You will get maternity only after two years.  Meaning you
took a policy today, next year you took a policy for two years.
When you renew for the third year, you are
eligible for the parenthood rider.  The
cover you will get here is up to ₹2 lakh which
you can claim.  And options that you can
choose.  ₹0000 One 2 Lakh
You can choose any option you want.
Your premium will be charged accordingly.
ICICI Low LMA is an additional rider to the Elevate.   There
is a waiting period of 2 years on maternity.
Cover up to Rs 1 lakh is available.  In Aditya Birla
Active Fit, if delivery is normal
then it is 40,000 secs and if delivery is normal then it is 60,000 secs.
In Anpal Singhana Sarva Uttam, covered up to 20%
of sum assured maximum ₹ lakh.  So you will get a maximum of ₹5 lakh.
You will get only 20% of the sum assured
and the waiting period is 36 months.
50,000 in Star Women Care
You will get up to 50,000 for maximum two
deliveries.  There will be a waiting period of 2 years in this,
you will get maternity cover after 2 years
but if you are taking a higher sum assured, a
policy of more than 15 lakhs, then the
waiting period will be reduced to one
year. You have an option to do that.
If we talk about new born baby cover, then
up to sum assured in Neevapa Aspire, as soon as
you take delivery, if you
take maternity benefit miracle benefit from this policy, then the
baby gets automatically added to the policy
and up to sum assured becomes their cover, so if there is
any hospitalization at the time of
baby's birth, then that is also covered and
payable, vaccination of the child
is not covered.  Miracle Benefit
covers vaccination for the mother.  Antenatal vaccinations,
which are prenatal vaccinations given to the mother,
are covered.  That is within the limit of Rs
75,000 which we talked about, maximum Rs 75,000.
Newborn
baby cover is not available in HDFC Urban Optima Secure.  You will have to
add the baby on 91st day.  In ICIC LBAD
Elevate, you can also take riders like
maternity cover and newborn baby expenses
vaccination expenses rider.  So the
cover for newborn baby is twice the
maternity cover and up to 90 days of the
birth.  If we have paid ₹1 lakh for maternity, then
you can claim ₹1 lakh for newborn baby expenses.
Also, vaccinations
covered up to 1% of sum assured up to a maximum of
₹10,000 per year.  And these
vaccinations are given as per WHO standards.  Aditya Birla
Active Fit has over and above base sum
assured.  Newborn baby expenses,
vaccination, stem cells, preservation, all these will
also be covered within the maternity limit.
All this will be covered under the normal rate of Rs 400 and cesarean rate of Rs 600.
In Manipal Cigna Sir Uttam, baby is covered
within the maternity limit and vaccination will also be
given within the maternity limit.
Newborn baby is also covered under Four Women Care
up to ₹50,000 from the date of delivery till 90
days of birth.  So you can claim up to ₹5 lakh for your
child.  There is any hospitalization
up to 90 days of birth.  So, there
is a separate option available in Niva Aspire
where you can multiply your cover.
And you can take a future guarantee that
you will be able to add a future spouse.  Which
is called future ready.  Meaning, if you
are single today and you take the Future Ready Rider, then
your spouse will be added in the future.
And your waiting periods will be carried forward to your
spouse.
And there is Fast Forward which allows
you to take cover for three years at once.  What we were
talking about 75,000 is 25,000 per year.
If you fast forward three years,
then you can claim three years of cover together in maternity, which
is Rs 75,000.  So now let us
also talk about the other benefits of these plans,
what are the benefits, what
are the eligibility criteria, who can take this policy
, what is the coverage scope and
what else is covered in this policy apart from maternity?
Independent detailed videos of these policies
are also available.  We are putting their links below.
You can refer any
plan if you feel that you want to take it.
But don't
forget to do your due diligence.  Buy the policy only after checking the policy wording and
knowing about the product in detail.
Now let's talk about Niva
Aspire.  Here we will talk about room rent
eligibility.  So room rent eligibility is as per
actuals.  Whatever actual expenses are incurred will be
borne by the insurance company.  We are
talking about this Titanium plan.  Then we will
talk about HDFC and Optima Secure, there is
no room rent capping.
Sum assured on actual amount.  Single
Private AC Room is available in ICIC LBA.  You
can get a room modifier.  If you want no room
capping or want a shared room.  There
is no capping in Aditya Bill Active Fit also.  You can opt for no room rent
capping but you
can take any room if you want.  Manipal Signal Sabha
Uttam has single private AC room.
You can also get room rank modification for any
room or shared accommodation.  In Star Health,
if you take a policy of Rs 5 lakh, then 1% of the
sum assured is given.
Take a policy of Rs 10, 15, 20, 25 lakh.  There is no capping if you take any room except sweet
and above category and policy of Rs 50 lakh or Rs 1 crore.
You can go for any room.  Minimum and
Maximum Entry Age When you go to buy a policy, there is a
minimum entry age
and there is also a maximum entry age.   The
minimum entry age in Neebopair is 18,
maximum is 65, children's age can be from 91 days
to 30 days dependent child can be added.
Then we will talk about HDFC R Go
Optima Secure. The minimum entry age is 18.   There
is no maximum limit.  Dependent children between 91 days to 25
years can be added.
Then ICIC Labrad Elevate can add child from 18 to 125 and
91 days to 30 years.
In Aditya Birla Active,
you cannot take this policy between 18 years to 45 years i.e. above 45 years.
So you can take it within 45 only.  Then comes
Manipal Signa Sarva
Uttam 18 Minimum.  There
is no maximum limit.  Dependent child between 91 days to 30 days.
Star Women Care has 18 to 75 ah
minimum age of 18.  The maximum entry age is 75 years.
Dependent Children 91 days to 25
years for male 30 years for female.  So, I would
like to tell you one thing about Star Women Care, here
only your woman can make the proposal for the
policy.  So is the Star Women Care Policy.  It is
specifically designed keeping in mind the needs of women.
So a women's proposal can be made for the
policy.  Minimum Maximum Sum Assured:
Sum assured of Rs 5 lakh to Rs 1 crore is available in Niva Aspire.
Sum assured ranging from Rs 5 lakh to Rs 2 crore
is available in HDFC Arbo Optima Secure.  ICICI Low LBA Delivered offers
options ranging from Rs 5 lakh to unlimited sum assured.  Aditya Birla Activ has
options ranging from Rs 5 lakh to Rs 1 crore.  Manipal
Cigna Sarva Uttam has options ranging from Rs 5 lakh to Rs 3
crore.  New Star Women
Care has options ranging from Rs 5 lakh to Rs 1 crore.
Policy Tenure.  So for
how many years can you take the policy?  Firstly, it is a one year
contract.  You
can also take a multi-tenure policy.  This means that you can pay premium for 2 years, 3
years, 4 years, 5 years
together.  Due to which the
company gives you some discount and your premium gets
locked for the next three to four to five
years.  So in Neema Aspire there is option of one year, two
year, three year.  HDFC Argo
Optima Secure also has one year, two year,
three year and super secure options
available which you can avail for three years.
Then ICICI Elevate One to Three Four
and Five Years option is available.  Aditya
Birla in Active One to Three Years.  Haripal
Signal Sarva also has one to three years.
One year, two year,
three year options are available in Star Women Care.  Now let's talk about
bonus, what bonus do you get?  If
you do not make a claim, you
get some incentives or if you are a loyal customer
of the insurance company, you get some incentives.
You get Booster Plus in Nivair.
We will talk about titanium.
More variants are available.  But here we are
talking about titanium.  If your
entry age is 18 to 35, then
you get booster benefit up to 10 times.  This means that your
sum assured will keep increasing every year.  And it will go up
to 10 times.
Up to five times if the entry age is 36 to 45 and
up to three times if the entry age is 46 plus.
HDFC Ergo Optima Secure has a plus
benefit which is 50% of sum assured.
Meaning, if you have a sum assured of Rs 10 today
and you do not use it, it will become Rs 15 next year.
And then it goes up to 20.  So
the maximum will go up to 20.  There is no no claim bonus here.
Another benefit here is
secure benefit.  In HDFC Argo Optima
Secure, your policy is counted two times
from day one.  Super Secure Is
Three Times From Day One.  So your security will
triple in 3 years.  Super
Secure will quadruple in 3 years.  And the
claim has nothing to do with it.  It will be the same every time.
You get no claim bonus in ICICI Low LBAD Elevate.  Which is
guaranteed cumulative bonus of 20% you will get
every year maximum up to 100%.  Here you
can also add power booster.  Due to which
your sum assured will increase by 100% every year and will
not reduce in case of claim.
In Aditya Birla Active Fit, your sum
assured will increase by 10% every year.  Maximum up to 100%
and will not be reduced in case of claim.
You can add piggy bank in Manipal Sinh Saravah
through rider, through which your sum
assured will keep increasing every year 100% then [ __ ]
star women care no claim bonus is of 20%,
maximum will go up to 100% and will not be reduced
in case of claim day care procedures,
then day care procedures
are covered in the policies up to sum of a shot domiciliary
hospitalization domiciliary hospitalization is
that the patient is in such a condition that he
cannot be taken to the hospital, so he has to be hospitalized at home
or
bed is not available in the hospital, then domiciliary
hospitalization is also covered in your policies,
AYUSH is covered.  AYUSH, Ayuda, Yoga,
Unani, Siddha, Homeopathy, their
hospitalization is covered.  Refill
Benefit Refill benefit is that if
your sum assured gets exhausted then it gets
refilled again, restored and
reinstated.  Reshore Plus in Nivapa Aspire gets
triggered with your first claim
and stays with you throughout the policy.
Suppose you have a policy of Rs 20 lakh
and you have fully utilized Rs 20 lakh, then
again Rs 20 lakh will be added to your policy
which you can use
for anything and this will continue for an unlimited number of times.
Restore Once
a Year is also available in HDFC Acco.  You
can convert to Unlimited Restore by paying a
nominal premium.
Unlimited restore is also available in ICIC LBA.  So I would
like to tell you about unlimited restore.  You
can claim for anything.  You can do this for same
illness, different illness, same person, different
person.  Aditya
Birla Active Fit also offers unlimited number
of times in a year for any illness.
You can add riders to Manipal Cigna Sarva Uttam.
Once a year restoration is available to you at Star Women Care.
If your sum assured gets exhausted
then once a year it will be restored.
Emergency road ambulance is covered up to the
sum assured as per actuals.
Similarly, HDFCO Optima Secure also
offers Edge Per Actuals.  ICICI
Lombard Elevate also covers
up to sum assured as per actuals. Aditya Birla
Active Fit covers road ambulance
if you are going to a network hospital.
If you are
not going to a network hospital, you will get ₹3000 per
hospitalization i.e. per event.
Manipal Singh Sarwaha is an Actual S in Uttam.
Covered up to some assured.
Star Women Care also covers up to sum
assured.  Then let's talk about emergency
air ambulance.  Emergency Air Ambulance is
covered in Nib Ace Fire,
up to the actual sum assured is the same. Your sum is also assured up to the same in HDFC Secure.
You can add it through rider in IC Lombard Elevate also.
Your air ambulance is not covered in Aditya Birla Active Fit.
You can add emergency air ambulance through rider in Manipal Cigna Sarvam.
10% of sum assured per year at Star Health:
You can use 10% of your sum assured for air ambulance.
And this is available
only for sum assured above Rs 10 lakh.
Annual health checkup.  So
preventive health checkups are also covered in your policies.
Niva Aspire has it inbuilt.
You can avail annual health checkup reimbursement of up to ₹10,000 on a cashless
basis from day
one.  You have up to ₹15,000 in HDFC Arbo.
It is on reimbursement.  But you
can claim this on renewal.  You took the policy today.
You can get preventive health checkup reimbursed after renewing the policy next year.
You can also avail of ICICI Low LBA Delivered through riders and
get your preventive health checkups on a cashless basis.
Once a year you
are covered under Aditya Birla Active Fit Plan which is cashless
only.  Once a year you will be added to Manipal
Cigna Sarva Uttam also through rider.
At Star Women Care also you
get preventive health checkup once a year.  Wellness
Benefits.  Neevapa offers wellness benefits of up to 30%.  This
means that
you
get a discount on renewal according to the number of steps you count.  This is
called Live Healthy Benefit up to 30%.
This is not available in HDFC Arbo.
Health returns of up to 30% are also available in ICICI Elevate and
you get health returns of up to 50% in Aitya Birla Activ.  Manipal
Cigna requires downloading up to 20% Wealthy app.
Accordingly, Star also has
its own wellness program in which
you get discounts up to 10% on the basis of
wellness points.  Pre and post
hospitalization expenses.  This means that there are some
expenses which are
covered before and after hospitalization.  So in Neema Bupa
Aspire 60 days before and 180 days after.
You can claim pre and post hospitalization expenses of 60 and 180 days in HDFC Ergo Optima Secure, 90 and 180 days in ICICI, 90 and 180 days in Aditya Birla, 90 and 180 days in Manipal Cigna and 60 and 90 days in Star Women Care.
Modern treatments, robotic
surgeries.  So the modern treatments which are done
due to the advancement of science, which are
robotic assisted surgeries, are
called modern treatments
robotic assisted surgeries. So,
up to sum assured is covered in Neema Aspire, up
to sum assured is also covered in HDFC Ergo Optima Secure, up to sum assured is also covered
in ICIC Lambar Elvet, up to sum assured
is also covered in Aditya Birla
Active Fit, up to sum assured is
also covered in Manipal Singhna Sarva
and there are limits in Star Women Care,
if it is a policy of 5 to 15 lakhs
then 50% of sum assured is available, if it is a policy of 20 to 50 lakhs
then 40 to 30% of sum assured is available and if it is a
policy of 50 lakhs to 1 crores then 30% of sum
assured is available.  Non-payable items
means non-payable items such as consumable
items are also covered in your policy.
You can add Neeva BPSR consumable items through your Safeguard Plus or Safeguard.  HDFC Arbo has
inbuilt protect benefit.
You can also add a claim protector to ICICI LBR.
To avail non-payable items cover.
Can also be added through rider in Aditya Birla Active Fit plan.
ManipalCigna Sarva
Uttam plan can also be added through rider
and is covered under Star Women Care.
Copayment There
is no copayment of any kind in the policies.  Voluntary
comment is available in some policies which are in
front of you.  You can add that if you
want to reduce the premium.  Let's take the
waiting periods.  So the
initial waiting period in every policy is 30 days.
You cannot take planned hospitalization for the first 30 days.
Slow
growing illness which we
call specific exclusions.  That
is not covered for two years.  Then there are pre-existing
conditions.
What is the waiting period for those who already have diseases?  There is
three years in Neevapass and you can reduce the
waiting period for some conditions. You can reduce the waiting period.
Add ons are available in these policies. There is
three years in HDFC Arbo Optima Secure also, there is
three years in ICICI Lo LBAD Elevate, there is
three years in Aditya Birla Activate and there is 36 months
in Manipal Cigna Sarvottam, there is a
waiting period of 2 years in Women Care for
pre-existing conditions. So now let us
review the maternity benefit,
what is the maternity benefit. In these policies, there is
Miracle Benefit in Neeva BPS which covers
your delivery expenses, antenatal
checkups which are
checkups related to pregnancy and maternity.  You get guaranteed coverage for vaccination, mother's
IVF, surrogacy, adoption, newborn
baby expenses and after nine months,
this is covered in this Titanium plan.
In the Parenthood Rider that we are talking about,
your maternity benefit is covered
from Rs 50,000 to Rs 2 lakh in HDFC and Optima Secure
and the waiting period is 2 years.  Here you
can add riders for maternity and newborn
baby coverage in ICICI LBA Elevate.  The waiting
period is 2 years.  We had told you that
1% of sum assured maximum ₹1 lakh up to
one year and the child's expenses are
covered twice under maternity cover up
to 90 days along with vaccinations.
In Aditya Birla Active Fit, maternity expenses
over and above sum are assured.
40,000 in normal delivery and 60,000 in C-section.
Vaccinations are included in your maternity limit.
And stem cell preservation
is also covered with in maternity limits.  Manipal
Signals Serva covers maternity and newborn
hospitalization expenses up to 20% of sum
assured.  The maximum is 5 lax.  Can be
added through rider.  And
in Star Women Care, the sum assured and the limit are
defined according to the sum assured.  If the
sum assured is ₹5 lakh then ₹10 to 20 lakh
then ₹1 crore sum
assured then ₹1 lakh becomes your maternity limit.
So in the end we will check
what is the premium of these plans?  So I am
sharing with you the premium with and without maternity benefit.
Wherever it is inbuilt, it will be mentioned as inbuilt.
You can see in the table below where we are adding on maternity benefit and what benefits we are getting.  Do
n't forget to do your new diligence.  Any maternity plan you
want to take.  But if you are planning for maternity then it is
highly recommended that
you should take a maternity plan.  Because
what happens is that many times in your corporate
you get maternity expenses.
But
here you get the coverage for newborn along with the
delivery cost.  So by chance, if the
child has any congenital issue then it becomes difficult to cover it outside.  There is
guaranteed
coverage here.  So it is advisable to go
for maternity plans.  If you are
planning maternity or planning for a child.
This was all from my side.   If
you want to reach out to us for any query, please do so.  You
can fill our WhatsApp number, email ID, contact number, a Google form.  Our team will connect you.   If
you want to give some comments,
want to give some feedback, share it in the comment
section.  And tell me on what should I make the next video.
Quick reminder before we go,
if you haven't subscribed to our channel yet
, do so.  So that
you get the right infection at the right time.